JAMELA SANCHEZ

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

437-566-9511

https://jamsanch26.github.io/myPortfolio/

897 Brimorton Drive, Scarborough ON, Canada

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, CSS, HTML, C++, Java, JavaScript

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Angular, Node.js, Express.js

Tools: GitHub, VS Code, IntelliJ, MySQL, Oracle SQL Developer

Databases: SQL, MongoDB

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN

Centennial College | Canada

2 Year College Diploma 2023-2024

BS IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Samar Colleges, Inc. | Philippines Bachelors Degree 2014-2018

REFERENCES

Timothy Cody

Collaborator, Magic Chef Project +1(732) 600-2227, timothybcody@gmail.com

Seyed M. Reza Dibaj

Professor, Centennial College 705-885-5858, rdibaj@my.centennialcollege.ca

Precina Maghari

QA Manager, Nyankids (Cambodia) Ltd. +639978462179, precina.maghari@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a dedicated Software Engineer with experience and extensive education in software design and application development. A fast learner with great time management, attention to detail, problem solving and multi-tasking skills. Strong work ethic in team or individual settings with excellent communication and interpersonal skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR QUALITY COORDINATOR

February 2020 - May 2023

- NyanKids (Cambodia) Ltd. | Cambodia
- Booking inspections factory audits and follow-up pre-final inspections.
- Attend PPM, keep and update all necessary documents and quality SOP.
- Responsible for monitoring QA/QC performance by gathering relevant data.
- Performs final inspections, and performance reporting; performs and monitors best practices and training factory staff.

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

October 2018 – January 2020

- © Teleperformance | Philippines
- Managed all customer inquiries and provided effective solutions to ensure satisfaction.
- Entered and maintained data from customers into various software programs accurately.
- Collaborated with team members to improve processes & enhance overall customer experience.
- Troubleshot equipment and system problems, escalating issues as necessary to ensure timely resolution

TICKET OFFICER ACCOUNTING CLERK

April 2018 – September 2018

Roperl Travel & Tours | Philippines

- Performing basic office tasks, such as filing, data entry, answering phones, processing the mail.
- Responsible for handling ticket reservations, cancellations, alterations, and informing customers
 when a flight has been delayed or cancelled.

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY INTERN

June 2017 – September 2017

SPI CRM INC. | Philippines

• Troubleshoot system & install/configure computer hardware operating systems & applications.

PROJECTS

GTA GARAGE DEALS

September 2024 – December 2024

O Centennial College | Canada

- The GTA Garage Deals is a web application developed as a group project during our Final Sem in the Software Engineering program at Centennial College. This application provides users with a streamlined platform to discover and participate in garage sales across (GTA).
- You can refer to GitHub repository; Frontend: https://github.com/ebatucentennial/garageapp-client & Backend: https://github.com/ebatucentennial/garage-app-server.git

THE MAGIC CHEF

June 2024 - August 2024

O Centennial College | Canada

- The Magic Chef is a web application developed during our third semester in my program, using React.js, Express.js, Node.js, and MongoDB. It offers a diverse collection of recipes customized to users' tastes and dietary needs.
- You can refer to repo at https://github.com/jamsanch26/WebAppProject.git

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Y ON-JOB-TRAINING MONITORING SYSTEM

Samar Colleges, Inc. | Philippines

- Won the 2018 Best Capstone Project Design and System Operation
- Well-Crafted Manuscript Project Design and System Operation
- Best Presentor Capstone Project Design and System Operation